GUILLERMO JULIÁN MORENO

PERSONAL INFORMATION

email gjulianm@outlook.com

other links Github — LinkedIn — Stack Overflow

DESCRIPTION

I'm always willing to learn new things, open to new approaches and ideas. I enjoy both working alone and in a team, either in an office or doing remote work, and I adapt quickly and easily to any environment, technology and organization.

I prefer challenging and hard projects that require more than just a little bit of thought and development. I'm also interested in researching and doing things that haven't been done.

WORK EXPERIENCE

December Intern

2013-Present High Performance Computing and Networking, UAM

Familiarizing myself with high performance networking, working on network dependency analysis, Linux driver development for traffic capture, numeric algorithms optimizations with OpenCL and network protocol reverse engineering and analysis.

January Freelance developer

2012-Present

Worked as a freelancer in various projects:

WINDOWS PHONE DEVELOPMENT Designed and developed from scratch Ocell (as a side project), Clases de Apoyo and Emergencias o66, an application for emergency assistance in Mexico. Assisted Softwhisper in the development of a Windows Phone application.

EGARANTE Designed and created the Firefox addon for eGarante. This addon allows users to digitally sign and timestamp any web page, including private ones (e.g. Twitter, Facebook). Developed a Python service to automatically sign user's conversations on social networks. Reference: Yago Jesús.

OTHER WORK Specialized in C# and networking in C/C++, I helped in the refactor and correction of existing projects and developed analyzers and dissectors for network traces, including parsers in restricted environments (e.g. OpenWRT routers).

January Editor at Genbeta, Weblogs SL

2010-Present

Writing about web and software in one of the most visited blogs in its category.

Author page at Genbeta

October Coordinator at Xataka Windows, Weblogs SL

2012-November

2014

Since its very beginning, I've been writer and coordinator at Xataka Windows, the Microsoft specialized spin-off of Xataka. I was responsible for the management of the publication's editorial team and for its contents

Author page at Xataka Windows

EDUCATION

Universidad Autónoma de Madrid

2009-2011 International Baccalaureate

LOE (spanish) Baccalaureate

Instituto Ramiro de Maeztu, Madrid

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Languages - Advanced knowledge C#, C, C++, Java, Python, LAT_EX.

Languages - Medium knowledge

Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Matlab, Mathematica, Bash, Common Lisp, Awk.

Frameworks and environments I've developed for

Angular.js, Azure, Firefox's Addon SDK, Glassfish, jQuery, Linux kernel, OpenCL, OpenWRT, Rails, Sage (mathematical), Windows Phone, Windows.

Technologies and software used

Sublime Text, Vim, Zsh, Visual Studio, Git, Github, TFS, Eclipse, Linux, OS X, Windows, Windows Phone, Android.

OTHER INFORMATION

Languages

Spanish · Mothertongue

ENGLISH · Advanced (conversationally fluent)

FRENCH · Basic (simple words and phrases only)

CATALAN · Basic (only spoken)

May 29, 2015